# **Antoine Soetewey**

antoinesoetewey.com

### Summary

I am a PhD student in statistics at UCLouvain in Belgium, within the Institute of Statistics, Biostatistics and Actuarial Sciences. My research interests focus on biostatistical procedures applied to cancer patients.

In parallel with my doctoral thesis, I am teaching assistant for several courses in statistics and probability at bachelor and master's level and I provide trainings and workshops in statistics and R programming for UCLouvain's technology platform for Statistical Methodology and Computing Service.

In my spare time, I write about statistics and some of its applications in R on my blog statsandr.com.

#### Education

2017 - Present PhD in statistics – UCLouvain, Belgium Thesis: Life and health actuarial pricing: a biostatistics approach (supervisors: Prof. Catherine Legrand and Prof. Michel Denuit) All publications, posters and talks available at antoinesoetewey.com/research 2015 - 2016MSc in econometrics & operations research – Maastricht University, Netherlands Thesis: Combining professional and survey forecasts for macroeconomic data (supervisor: Prof. Nalan Basturk) 2013 - 2015**MSc in economics** – KULeuven, Belgium Thesis: Negativity bias and framing effect in charity donations: a field experiment (supervisor: Prof. Jo Swinnen) Aug - Sep 2014 Faculty exchange - University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, USA 2010 - 2013BSc in economics & management sciences – UCLouvain, Belgium

### Teaching and consulting experience

2017 – Present **Teaching assistant in statistics** – UCLouvain, Belgium See all courses at antoinesoetewey.com/teaching

2018 – Present	Consultant and instructor in statistics & R programming – SMCS & easystat.be Statistical and data analysis consulting for professionals, academics and students Instructor for UCLouvain's university certificates "Introduction to data analysis with R", "Junior data analyst" and "Practice of statistics with R"
	Industry experience
2016 - 2017	Data scientist – Business & Decision, Belgium
	Involved in several projects focusing on data science and data visualization
2015	European public affairs intern – BNP Paribas, Belgium
2015	Audit intern – Deloitte, Luxembourg
	Leadership experience
2017 – Present	International tennis chair umpire – International Tennis Federation
	Work regularly as a chair or line umpire on major tennis events across the world
2016 – Present	Committee member – Association Francophone de Tennis, Belgium

# Technical skills & languages

#### **Software**

R (RStudio, R Markdown, Shiny), GitHub/GitLab,  $\LaTeX$ , Python See all projects at antoinesoetewey.com/software

## Languages

French (native), English (fluent), Dutch (intermediate)